<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Code Chauffeur</title>
    <link>https://codechauffeur.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Code Chauffeur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>© Emmanuel Awotunde</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://codechauffeur.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Custom Validation Rules to Adonis Validator</title>
      <link>https://codechauffeur.com/how-to-add-custom-validation-rules-to-adonis-validator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codechauffeur.com/how-to-add-custom-validation-rules-to-adonis-validator/</guid>
      <description>If you are reading this article, I assume you must have used AdonisJs or you must have heard about the framework. AdonisJs is a NodeJs web framework that was inspired by Laravel. The framework was modeled after Laravel.
Like most robust frameworks, AdonisJs comes with a validator module that helps you in validating data (usually user input). However, the default validator does not come with every possible rule, you sometimes have to implement your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benefits of Being in a Community as a Developer</title>
      <link>https://codechauffeur.com/benefits-of-being-in-a-community-as-a-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Mar 2020 22:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codechauffeur.com/benefits-of-being-in-a-community-as-a-developer/</guid>
      <description>This article was previously published on Medium in May 2017.
Covenant University Students and the facilitators during forLoopCU. Photo credit: Rotimi Okungbaye forLoopCU was the first developers’ meetup I attended. This was when my growth as a web developer actually started.
I started learning web development last year 2016 after I finished my first year at the university (Computer Science). I learnt the basics of web development using HTML, CSS and JavaScript during my SIWES at Plat Technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Reach Me</title>
      <link>https://codechauffeur.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://codechauffeur.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>You can reach me via email at awotunde.emmanuel1@gmail.com. You can also send me a DM on twitter @olaoluwa_98. I respond faster to mails because, why not?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>